

M.S.C. STUDENT

Hacettepe University

□+90 554 814 52 99 | 🜌 m.goktu66@gmail.com | 🖸 0000-0002-8507-9015 | 🖸 mehmetgoktug | 🛅 mehmetgoktug | 💆 mehmetgoktug

About Me_

I am currently working in İzmir Metropolitan Municipality. I took part in different projects from agriculture to animal husbandry, from afforestation to nature-based solutions. At the same time as a master's student in the Division of Ecology at Hacettepe University, I'm exploring "Spatio-temporal Patterns of Lightning-Induced Wildfires in Turkey". During my undergraduate studies, I took part in various field research projects across the Anatolia, covering fire ecology, plant functional traits, nomadic pastoralism, raptor migration, breeding birds, and large mammals. As an enthusiast for open and reproducible science, I like to write R, Python and Bash scripts, especially for spatial analysis.

Experience

İzmir Metropolitan Municipality

İzmir, Turkey

BIOLOGIST

03.2021-Present

• I am working ecological animal husbandry, agriculture, afforestation, landscape designing and nature based solutions - NBS in various projects, such as Mera İzmir, Başka Bir Tarım Mümkün, Bir Fidan Bir Dünya, Yaşayan Parklar and HORIZON (CARDIMED-Climate Adaptation and Resilience Demonstrated in the Mediterranean Region). I took an active role in collecting, processing and spatial analysis and modelling of the data.

Hacettepe University

Ankara, Turkey

Undergraduate Research Assistant

09.2015-01.2021

'Mersin, Karaman, Konya, Ankara',

• I have worked as an undergraduate research assistant on fire ecology, seed germination and plant functional traits projects in the FEL (Functional Ecology Lab) at Hacettepe University with Çağatay Tavşanoğlu, Cansu Ülgen and Gökhan Ergan.

Yolda Initiative

Turkey

FIELD BIOLOGIST 03.2019-03.2020

• I worked from March 2019 to November 2019 as a field biologist in field study on pastoralist's goat herds in Mersin in the Nomadic Pastoralism Effects on Seed Dispersal Project. After the field studies, I worked on this project's lab works. The project was run with partnership Yolda Initiative and Hacettepe University.

Doğa Derneği - Birdlife Turkey

Adana

FIELD BIOLOGIST 09.2018-09.2019

• I worked as a birdwatcher on the Sarımazı Raptor Migration Count in the Egyptian Vulture New LIFE project (LIFE16 NAT/BG/000874).

• Tworked as a birdwatcher on the Sanmazi Raptor Migration Count in the Egyptian vulture New Life project (Life 16 NAT/BG/000814).

Hacettepe University
Undergraduate Research Assistant

Ankara 09.2018

• I worked as a field study assistant in a research project on Quercus aucheri. We have worked in Aydın, Muğla and Antalya cities, almost all distribution range this species.

Education

Hacettepe University

Ankara, Turkey

MASTER OF SCIENCE - MS, ECOLOGY

2021-Present

Hacettepe University

Ankara, Turkey

Bachelor's degree, Biology

Anadolu University

Eskişehir, Turkey

ASSOCIATE'S DEGREE - AGRICULTURE

2020-Present

Volunteering

havadelisi.com

Turkev

2018-Present

• I am an editor in havadelisi.com and it's social media accounts.

MEHMET GÖKTUĞ ÖZTÜRK · CURRICULUM VITAE

SEPTEMBER 2023

FDITOR

Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey

FIELD BIOLOGIST

2017-2018

Lives valuation as hirdwatcher in the Investigating the Riediversity of Lake Eymir Area's Forest and Steppe Essevitems and Determining Con

I was volunteer as birdwatcher in the Investigating the Biodiversity of Lake Eymir Area's Forest and Steppe Ecosystems and Determining Conservation Priority Zones Project in METU's Birdwatching Club(OKGT).

Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey

FIELD BIOLOGIST

• I was volunteer as birdwatcher in the Searching for White-headed Duck (Oxyura leucocephala) Breeding and Wintering Grounds in Central Anatolia and Monitoring of Its Populations Project(Mohamed bin Zayed Species project number 182515710).

WWF-Türkiye Ankara, Turkey

FIELD BIOLOGIST

2016-2017

2018-2019

• I was volunteer as a birdwatcher in the European Breeding Bird Atlas Project 2 (EBBA 2).

Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry

Bolu, Turkey

Undergraduate Research Assistant

08.2016

• I was volunteer as an assistant of wildlife biologist in the Impact of Anatolian Motorway on Large Mammals project with Ali Onur Sayar.

Skills_

COMPUTER SKILLS

• R | Python | Bash | AWK | GDAL/OGR | QGIS | SAGA GIS | GRASS GIS | GEE | ArcGIS | SQL | GIT | Office Programs | Markdown

OTHER SKILLS

• Ecology | Biogeography | Spatial Analysis | Remote Sensing | Data Analysis | Data Entry | Field Work | Birdwatching

Languages_

- · Turkish (Native)
- English (B1)

References_

- Engin Yılmaz | Yolda Initiative | e-mail: engin@bican.net
- Prof. Dr. Utku Perktaş | Professor in Division of Ecology, Department of Biology, Hacettepe University, Turkey | Research Associate in Division of Vertebrate Zoology, Department of Ornithology, American Museum of Natural History, USA | e-mail: perktas@hacettepe.edu.tr
- Prof. Dr. Çağatay Tavşanoğlu | Professor in Division of Ecology, Department of Biology, Hacettepe University, Turkey | e-mail: ctavsan@hacettepe.edu.tr
- Dr. İrem Tüfekcioğlu | Forest Ecologist | e-mail: iremtuf@gmail.com